Google just released Gemini 2.0
experimental model which is probably the
first multimodel model that support both
image understanding and generation you
can upload image and give it a prompt
the model will respond back not just
text but also a generated image and we
already seeing loads of wild examples
from people where you can send image of
model and image of close and ask it to
combine into a new image you can even
upload image like this and ask it to
extract the passport photo of one of the
person in the image in a high fality
Manner and it even have accountability
to generate multiple images in a row so
that it can almost generate different
frames within a animation or GIF and
overall the image quality seems really
promising but most importantly this
experimental model is available VI the
API and as we know gerini model's cost
is extremely cheap compared with open Ai
and Cloud which is around 96% cheaper
than the GPD 40 model and we already
seen people building some really
interesting application
like a AI native Photoshop where users
can just upload image and just chat to
the AI and ask it to update image for it
or a gift maker where you can ask Gemini
to generate multiple frames of a
animation and putting together a gift
and those are just the beginning that's
why today I want to show you how can you
utilize Gemini model to building some
truly interesting use case and the
example I will take you through is how
did I use Gemini 2.0 experimental model
and also connect to one 2.0 which is one
most powerful image to video model they
can generate really high quality videos
based on image so that we can build some
sort of commercial products for
e-commerce site to Chad to Gemini to
generate a p shot that they are happy
with and then use 1 2.1 to generate
quick P shots without further Ado let's
get it firstly Let's test out how good
Gemini 2.0 experiment Moto actually is
so they do provide a few example use
case and prompt some of them is like
image editing where you can upload a
image course song and ask it to adding
some chocolate toppings as well as this
visual story generator that you can ask
Gemini to generate an actual story with
the image for each SC but also want to
try out some use case myself for I can
upload this image and tell it to change
the flag behind the man to USA flag
awesome so you can see the result is
actually extremely good even though when
you're look into details some details
face does change a little bit but it is
majority the same and it is able to
change just the spe flag and I can also
give another try I upload this sketch
and I give Pro mix this sketch into 3D
render colorful style and it would be
doing a pretty good job and I can
continue promp it change the hair color
to be red and make him smile okay so
this part does look a bit weird or
change back and then say don't change
the face a lot but make him smile okay
so this time it does looks a better cool
I found that normally it does really
high quality image generation at first
shot and the more more turns you have in
this chat lower the quality will be and
in the end I also really want to try the
gift use case so generate five frames of
GIF in a 2D pixel games of a dragon
monster cool so this looks really
awesome except the last two image does
look a little bit different but I'm
pretty sure I can just change the prompt
and make it consistent and you can
pretty easily build application that
just putting them together into a GI
generator so here is enough test but
overall what I found is that it does
really good job in terms of image
generation and keep the character
consistent across different images but
it performed less good when conversation
became longer basically the more you
prompt it the worst performance it get
but overall really impressive and I
can't totally see how this enable more
people to be able to do image editing
jobs and very likely people can build a
new type of Photoshop or Cana experience
with those real multimodal model
abilities but the most interesting thing
is let's try to use Gemini 2.0 API to
create some prototypes so I just open up
a new project cursor and let's first say
add a EMV file to store the Gemini API
key here and you can get API key on
Google AI studio and let's create a
Gemini experimental. py file and first
they import a few libraries are going to
use and then create a Gemini client and
then I'll create a user prompt message
so this is the type that you use to
create a message history in gini and our
pass this conversation history to the
Gemini 2.0 model where the config here
saying the response modality should be
both text and image and we can probably
expect this to extend to audio and video
later and in the end depends on what
type of response it return if the text
will print out text but if the image we
save this image file so let's give a try
I will do python Gemini experimental. py
all right so you can see that it
generate an image of cat here so this
how you can get Gemini 2.0 to generate
image but what if if you want to pass a
image response uh into gimini as well
well what you can do is inside Parts
here you can also add a types. part from
bite and data equal to pass lip. pass
generated image.png read bites and M
type equal to image PNG and this should
get the cat image we have here and then
we can update prompt to make this cat
hair like a red color and let's try
again cool you can see the cast hair
color turned into red color so this how
you can utilize Gemini model to both
read the image and also general image
and next let's learn how can we turn
this image into a video using one 2.1
model so we're going to use this 1 2.1
model host down replicate if you don't
know what replicate is replicate is like
the model marketplace where they have
tons of latest AI models across image
Generation video generation and lar L
model itself you can either use those
existing model models directly or you
can find your own model with fairly
limited amount of data set required and
have a cloud service that you can call
anytime so after you create a replicate
account we can just click on this model
they we're going to use which is 1 12.1
480p and we can click on API page and
select Python and I will firstly add
replicate token to mymv file here and
then I'll create a new one going 2.1 and
I can just copy this code example here
the only difference is that here it is
using a image URL but we actually want
to rate a image from the local dis so I
turn this into a function where it can
open a local image pass on to this
specific replicate model and save the
video here and I can test it by running
this function using this cat photo that
we generated and give a prompt cat is
looking around if you haven't installed
replicate yet making sure to do the PIP
install replicate and then we can round
the script cool so you can see this a 5
Seconds video generated so we have both
endpoint working the last thing we want
to do is we'll create a quick
web application using streamlet that can
simulate the whole chat experience so
our first create a general function for
General response from Gemini we it
detect if is first message that user try
to send if it is then we'll attach the
image user uploaded as part of cont as
well as a promp and pend messages and
generate to return the response
meanwhile I will also turn the replicate
model calling into this generate video
function where it will try to call the
replicate model and return the video
pass when it's ready and also a helper
function to reset the video state or
also create a utility. py which has a
bunch of utility function like save the
binary file process upload image and
check if the image are duplicated and in
the end I use streamlit to quickly build
a GUI and if you don't know what
streamlit is it is a python framework
that allow you to quickly build user
interface and spin up a web app that you
can share with other so I created app.py
importing all the packages and the
library that we have set a title and we
will also Define list of state to keep
track of what kind of message has been
sent what image user has uploaded as
well as image Gemini return and videos
when 2.1 return now weer the title
Define sidebar where users can upload
list of image and we display the list of
image and update State and then create
two tabs with the tab one will be the
chat experience where user can chat to
Gemini to iterate the image and we'll
have some logic here to display the chat
history as well as logic after users
click Send message and second tab for
the video generation so all the image
that Gemini return will be displayed for
the user here for them to select and
they can basically select image that
they want to generate the video and once
the video is generated we display the
video here on the screen and once it
finished I can quickly do streamlit Rong
app.py and you can see here we have a
web app that is ready to use I can
upload some image I can promp it
generate product shot of hand wearing
the bracelet you can see here it
generate a pretty good image of a man
wearing this bracelet and I can also
prompt it to say change the hand to be
black man's head and now generate new
image with a black man hand so you can
see that users can use this chat
interface to keep iterating the phoshop
and if I go to video generation there
are two image that I can use to generate
video so I will select the second one
give a prompt a p shot at showcasing the
bracelet now get video generated so this
is how you can build a example per using
Gemini 2.0 API if you want to get more
in depth about how to use this API and
step-by-step process of reild the exact
example I showcase here you can join the
AI Builder Club Community and building
where I share tips and tricks of
building AI applications and Vibe coding
every week and for people who join right
now you can also get a $100 free
replicated credits limit to 1,000 AI bu
club members plus you have this
community of top AI Builders who are
launching their own AI products right
now so you can come and post any
question that challenge you have where
me and others will just jump on and
share our learnings I have put the link
in the description below for you to join
I hope you enjoy this video thank you
and I see you next time